Liam Norton - Technical Specialist



Address: 23 Ironstone Way, Manchester, M28 3BB

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/liam-norton-335139b3/

Website: https://lwnorton.com/

Mobile: +44 7913696444 Email: liamn2011@gmail.com

Profile

I bring over 10 years of comprehensive career experience, with more than 7 years specifically in software technology. Throughout my journey, I've showcased proficiency in various roles, highlighting a commitment to continuous learning. My track record of swiftly learning and applying new abilities has been instrumental in steering a successful career. I've been a key player in delivering new system and system integration projects, contributing to revenue growth, and reducing operational costs. My leadership style is collaborative, emphasising effective communication and empowering cross-functional teams to achieve collective success.

Skills

- SOL
- Node JS
- C#
- Data Analysis
- System Integration Modeling
- Leadership

- Javascript
- Express JS
- Python
- Requirements Elicitation
- Integration/Solution Documentation
- HTML & CSS
- React JS
- Rest API's
- SaaS
- Data analysis

Certification

- BCS Certificate in Business Analysis Practice
- CISI Level 3 Award for introduction to Investment
- **BCS Certificate in Requirements Engineering**
- CISI Level 4 FSA Regulation and Professional Integrity
- · BCS Foundation Certificate in Business Analysis

Applications

- Visual Studio
- GitHub
- AWS S3, Athena, Lambda
- Visual Studio Code
- Figma
- Swagger

- SQL Server Management Studio
- Atlassian Jira, Confluence
- Lucid Charts/ MS Visio

Experience

Position - Principal Integration Consultant - Jan 2023 to Present Remote

Company - Aptitude Software - Manchester

Responsibilities:

- · Elicitate and analyse functional, non-functional and regulatory (GDPR, PCI) requirements, providing integration and architectural consultancy to enterprise clients with complex tech stacks.
- Construct comprehensive technical documentation detailing system integration diagrams, data requirements, sample code, as well as self built working Proof of Concept's (POC) specifically designed to aid client system architects and lead developers
- Develop and implement coding solutions to overcome project obstacles, including using cloud architecture to devise solutions ensuring deadlines are met.
- Exploring core platform functionality and collaborating with product and technical teams to develop robust solutions.
- Provide technical leadership to the integration team and cross-functional teams, guiding the implementation of best practices and approving solutions.
- Lead, mentor, and develop the integration team to enhance their skills and foster continuous improvement, leveraging the use of OKRs (Objectives and Key Results) to enhance the way we work.
- Responsible for the recruitment of new talent, which includes designing and implementing a technical problem-solving skills test for recruits.
- Designing and implementing process improvements to reduce time, cost, and resources, aiming to provide a shorter and smoother client onboarding
- Continuously assessing the client documentation hub in collaboration with Product Marketing to ensure that the documentation maintains the necessary level of detail to facilitate a seamless integration for clients/partners.

Projects Delivered:

- Successfully implemented subscription, billing, and logistics functions for German publishers, supporting integrations with multiple systems. Clients include Aschendorff, Schwabische, and Nordkurier, unlocking recurring revenue streams.
- Built a variety of custom solutions, including automated future cancellation solution, delivery stop refund retry solution, subscription upgrade solution, automated custom refund data population solution, subscription quantity & price adjustment solution, and more.
- Developed a web application test to assess new recruits' abilities to work through code-related issues.

Position - Implementation Consultant - Sep 2020 to Dec 2022 Hybrid



Company - Aptitude Software / MPP Global - Manchester

Responsibilities:

- Conduct business analysis to define the project scope and elicit client system/ functional & non-functional business requirements.
- Deliver technical specifications utilising sequence diagrams for system integrations involving REST APIs.
- Serve as the subject matter expert in REST APIs and best practices for integration.
- Configure the platform according to client requirements, testing the configurations in UAT and production environments.
- Provide guidance and support to internal client support teams for resolving complex system problems, including issues related to database locks, API performance, client front-end problems, and more
- Investigate platform (C#) bugs/gaps and provide fixes to internal developers.

- Plan and execute complex client data migrations.
- Daily use of the Postman application to create easily understandable API collections, incorporating automated tests and visualisations.
- Develop proof of concepts to aid internal and external development teams in their build and testing processes.

Projects Delivered:

- Successfully implemented subscription, billing, and 3D Secure payment functions for clients, including Channel 4, Manchester United TV, Juventus TV, and Live Now, unlocking recurring revenue streams.
- Provided expertise in clients' efforts to upgrade the existing code base for 3D Secure v2 payments, which included delivering a self-built payment page proof of concept (POC) for guidance. Additionally, I constructed developer documentation and conducted code reviews.
- Provided support and monitoring for live streaming events from an infrastructure perspective, which included monitoring database performance, web/application server performance, and RPM rates.

Position - Business Analyst - Sep 2018 to Aug 2020 On-Site



Company - AJ Bell - Manchester

Responsibilities:

- Agreed on project scope and objectives before employing various requirement elicitation techniques to extract and identify functional and non-functional requirements. These techniques included workshops, shadowing, management interviewing, data analysis, and procedure analysis.

 Employing As-Is and To-Be process modeling techniques, such as BPMN, to illustrate both current and future business and system processes.
- Construct visual prototypes and wireframes while developing software requirement specifications.
- Collaboratively worked with the development scrum team to create user stories, facilitate refinement sessions and defined the criteria for definition of done (DOD). Actively managed and prioritised the project backlog with a focus on business value

Projects Delivered:

- Led the internal asset/cash transfer department project, where we successfully implemented a new web application supporting CRUD functionality. This initiative improved efficiency and reduced customer churn by introducing a system that offers real-time tracking, analytics, and an overview of completed tasks, outstanding tasks, and responsibilities.
- Led the analysis and delivery of a third-party integration to a asset purchasing platform 'Clearstream,' resulting in cost savings.

Position - Business Improvement Analyst - Jul 2017 to Aug 2018 On-Site



Company - AJ Bell - Tunbridge Wells

Responsibilities:

- Collaborate with internal stakeholders to identify efficiencies in business and system processes.
- Develop system macros for internal teams to automate the input of large datasets.
- Analyse, configure, test, and implement new system configurations for enhanced efficiency.

Projects Delivered:

- Led an existing third-party supplier integration project (Cofunds), which involved configuration and data migration changes, ensuring the continuous use of the platform by the operational teams.
- A cost reduction project aimed at lowering the per-transaction cost by implementing an automated internal asset bulking solution.

Position - Test Analyst - Mar 2016 to Jun 2017 On-Site



Company - AJ Bell - Tunbridge Wells

Responsibilities:

- Collaborate with developers to formulate and align on acceptance criteria for user stories.
- Construct and execute test plans along with software test scripts.
- Manage data and configuration requirements for test scenarios.
- Responsible for managing user acceptance testing, including providing guidance to business users in constructing test scripts, testing, and identifying defects.

Projects Delivered:

- New Calastone third-party integration testing.
- Core third-party platform upgrade testing.

Other Positions

- AJ Bell (Tunbridge Wells) Collective Investment Dealer Oct 2014 to Feb 2016
- AJ Bell (Tunbridge Wells) Dealing Services Agent Oct 2013 to Sep 2014
- JN Financial (London) New Business Advisor Feb 2013 to May 2013

Education

Dates	Place of study	Qualification
2009 - 2012	The University of Hull	Bsc Economics
2007 - 2009	Tollbar 6th Form	A Level - Economics, Business Studies, Physical Education
2002 - 2007	Tollbar Business and Enterprise College	10 GCSE's